Asadullah Farooqi

Junior software engineer

+923111686184 asadullah.itcgcs@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

NHIIT, Multan — *Python Instructor*

DEC 2016 - MAR 2017

I didn't stay for long in multan so that's i quite the job shortly. During this time I also one of their course CCNA.

Akbar Computer Academy, Loralai — IT Instructor

NOV 2015 - MAR 2016

I was an instructor of hardware and some other computer basics.

EDUCATION

Boys Degree College, Loralai — *Fsc(Faculty of Science)*

MAR 2013 - AUG 2015

In Pakistan after the passing the 10th grade two years of college comes which can be refers as Higher Secondary School. And I took the Mathematics as my field of study.

Farooqi Public High School, Ziarat — *Matriculation*

MAR 2011 - AUG 2012

I got A grade in the final. In other words 70%+.

PROJECTS

Inventory Web App — asadliam.pythonanywhere.com

This app is for wholesalers who need some kinda tool which will help them to work through their calculations and ledgers. After creating profile user can add company and company can have one or multi stores depend on business. And each store have customers, suppliers, imports and exports.

SKILLS

Python, Django, Flask,
HTML5, CSS3, Git, JavaScript,
C/C++, Algorithm design,
Bootstrap 4, Basic Data
Analysis & machine learning,
Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib.

Links

Website

https://github.com/Asadullah Farooqi/Asad.github.io.git

GitHub

https://github.com/Asadullah Faroogi/

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/asadullah-farooqi-0bb080111

Twitter

@AsadullahItcgcs

LANGUAGES

English, Urdu, Pashto, Persian (Farsi)

SUMMARY

I am a self-taught, highly passionate computer programmer and hobbyist. I've used a vast amount of online resources to learn various aspects of computer science in which I have a deep interest. My primary source of computer science knowledge has been the MIT Opencourseware. From there I've attended several fundamental computer science courses including data structures and algorithms(6.006), programming(6.0001, 6.0002), computer security(6.858), AI(6.034), Adv Data Structures(6.851), Adv Algorithms(cs 224) and some more.

My primary expertise is in advanced Python programming and writing Django/Flask based web applications.

It's been over a year now that i am scratching the surface of Machine learning. I am able to work on basic models of machine learning. I have strong grip on statistics, Mathematics like Linear algebra, Multivariable calculus for machine learning.